<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thomas Coopman - Infinite Tree</title>
    <link>https://infinitetree.eu/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thomas Coopman - Infinite Tree</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 15:00:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://infinitetree.eu/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bank Kata in Ocaml - Part 3: injecting a clock with Functors</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/25/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml---part-3-injecting-a-clock-with-functors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 15:00:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/25/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml---part-3-injecting-a-clock-with-functors/</guid>
      <description>So at the end of part 2 we said we don&amp;rsquo;t like that we have to add the date as part of the public API. Which makes sense for a public bank terminal, we do a deposit or withdrawal now.
So we&amp;rsquo;ll want to remove on from deposit and withdrawal. But where do the dates come from now? Let&amp;rsquo;s introduce a Clock module:
Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can rewrite our test to adapt to this new API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bank Kata in Ocaml - Part 2: implementing the kata</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/25/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml---part-2-implementing-the-kata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 14:45:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/25/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml---part-2-implementing-the-kata/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 we&amp;rsquo;ve set everything up, let&amp;rsquo;s implement the kata now. If we check the readme we can see a simple acceptance test, let&amp;rsquo;s start with that.
We create a file test/account_test.ml:
open! Base open! Stdio let%expect_test &amp;#34;Printing the statements should contain all transactions&amp;#34; = Lib.Account.create () |&amp;gt; Lib.Account.deposit ~amount:1000.0 ~on:&amp;#34;10/01/2012&amp;#34; |&amp;gt; Lib.Account.deposit ~amount:2000.0 ~on:&amp;#34;13/01/2012&amp;#34; |&amp;gt; Lib.Account.withdrawal ~amount:500.0 ~on:&amp;#34;14/01/2012&amp;#34; |&amp;gt; Lib.Account.print; [%expect{| date || amount || balance 14/01/2012 || -500.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bank Kata in Ocaml: Part 1 setting everything up</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/23/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml-part-1-setting-everything-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 16:45:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/08/23/the-bank-kata-in-ocaml-part-1-setting-everything-up/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this small series of blogs is to implement the Bank kata in OCaml, doing it test and type driven and try to have a clean design. We&amp;rsquo;ll try to implement the kata with outside-in tests. My personal goal is to learn some OCaml along the way. I won&amp;rsquo;t be going into every detail of OCaml, but if you have some experience with an ML language, you should be able to follow along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My summary of DDD Europe 2018</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/02/03/my-summary-of-ddd-europe-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 16:25:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2018/02/03/my-summary-of-ddd-europe-2018/</guid>
      <description>Well, that was a blast. DDD Europe 2018 is already over. And I loved it! Because I had lovely conversations, great insights and good learnings, I had the idea to create a summary, mostly for myself.
Pre conference workshop DIY Event Sourcing Tooling A pre conference workshop by Marijn Huizendveld on Tuesday and Wednesday.
This workshop about making your own event sourcing tooling was not exactly what I expected it to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I choose Bucklescript</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/10/28/why-i-choose-bucklescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 08:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/10/28/why-i-choose-bucklescript/</guid>
      <description>On the meetups I attend, some people know me as the Elm guy. Yet, when reading the title of this post, you can see that I&amp;rsquo;m going for Bucklescript lately.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to explain my choice for Bucklescript. If you are in doubt, maybe some points in this post can help, but my advice would be to just try and research both languages and see for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating bucklescript with typescript</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/09/30/integrating-bucklescript-with-typescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 18:19:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/09/30/integrating-bucklescript-with-typescript/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Bucklescript (and Reason) over Elm for various reasons (Something I might blog about later). In this post I&amp;rsquo;m exploring integrating Bucklescript with Typescript.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a blank typescript project with webpack You can find the inital commit of a Typescript project here.
There is nothing special in this commit, some npm dependencies: source-map-loader, ts-loader, typescript, webpack, webpack-dev-server. The ts-config.json file is generated with tsc --init, nothing is changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A big ball of frontend</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/09/27/a-big-ball-of-frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 14:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/09/27/a-big-ball-of-frontend/</guid>
      <description>Tonight I&amp;rsquo;m giving a talk at Fronteers about Frontend microservices. Mind you, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go into what a microservice is, so a talk about Frontend services is fine as well.
What is important for me is that we&amp;rsquo;re not building a big ball of frontend. We&amp;rsquo;re paying so much attention to having a good architecture on the backend, with lots of (micro)services but at the same time, we&amp;rsquo;re building one huge single page application (SPA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring aggregate boundaries in event sourced systems</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/02/08/exploring-aggregate-boundaries-in-event-sourced-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 20:44:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/02/08/exploring-aggregate-boundaries-in-event-sourced-systems/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m exploring some ways of modelling aggregate boundaries in an event sourced system. This is mostly to crystallise some thoughts that I had after some event storming sessions, but it might be interesting to someone else.
The domain I&amp;rsquo;m using in this post is the domain that Michel Grootjans and I have created for the workshop Playing with projections (We already gave it a few times, for example at DDD Europe and will also give a session at I T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/01/03/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 19:18:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2017/01/03/2017/</guid>
      <description>The year is over, a new year has come.
I know, New Year is an arbitrary point in time but it is a tradition to look back on the past year and have some resolutions for the year to come.
So at this arbitrary point in time, lets look back and forward
2016 I&amp;rsquo;m going to make this short, because I mostly want to look forward!
 Became an independent software consultant Bought a house with my girlfriend Read lots of books Became a teamleader Lots of other cool stuff  2017 Last month I read Building Jarvis from Mark Zuckerberg where he builds himself a Jarvis in 100 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Phoenix review</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/06/26/programming-phoenix-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 10:49:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/06/26/programming-phoenix-review/</guid>
      <description>Elixir and Phoenix crossed my path multiple times last year. I read a really interesting tutorial on building a web framework from scratch. Furthermore, Phoenix is really popular as an Elm backend, so I decided it was time to dive a bit deeper and learn myself some Phoenix.
It just happens that Program Phoenix by by Chris McCord, Bruce Tate, and José Valim was published recently, so this seemed like a good opportunity to learn more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explain Manillen with types and Elm</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/18/explain-manillen-with-types-and-elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 21:01:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/18/explain-manillen-with-types-and-elm/</guid>
      <description>At Domain Drive Design Europe I met the wonderful @Felienne. In the evening we played the card game bridge (a game the Felienne likes a lot). As a West-Vlaming I love the card game Manillen more, of course, and we joked about it. Felienne has the ambition to create an AI to compete at the world championship of Computer Bridge, and I have joked about some similar ambitions of mine at Socrates Belgium, but this blog post has a much more humble goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling money in Elm</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/12/modelling-money-in-elm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 22:28:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/12/modelling-money-in-elm/</guid>
      <description>After reading the blog post of Mathias Verraes (@mathiasverraes) on (Type Safety and Money)[http://verraes.net/2016/02/type-safety-and-money/], and after doing a real short modelling attempt in Haskell at Socrates Belgium, I wanted to try to model Money in Elm.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go to deep and too far so I&amp;rsquo;ve set some basic constraints for myself:
 You cannot add money of different currencies (you need an explicit conversion) - Add constraint We also want a Price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/12/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 21:28:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2016/04/12/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the my new site written in hugo. While busy, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up https via letsencrypt. (see tutorial. You can find the source code of the blog here. This is a reboot of my site, and an attempt to blog some more.
So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s start blogging :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor till you drop</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2015/12/04/refactor-till-you-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2015/12/04/refactor-till-you-drop/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Iteration 1 function getSymbol(symbolName) { return &amp;#39;replace&amp;#39;; } function escapeRegExp(string) { return string.replace(/([.*+?^=!:${}()|\[\]\/\\])/g, &amp;#34;\\$1&amp;#34;); } function SymbolReplacer(s) { this.alreadyReplaced = []; this.stringToReplace = s; } //iteration 1 https://sites.google.com/site/unclebobconsultingllc/one-thing-extract-till-you-drop SymbolReplacer.prototype.replace = function() { var symbolPattern = /\$([a-zA-Z]\w*)/g; var matches; while (matches = symbolPattern.exec(this.stringToReplace)) { var symbolName = matches[1]; if (getSymbol(symbolName) !== null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; this.alreadyReplaced.indexOf(symbolName) === -1) { this.alreadyReplaced.push(symbolName); var toReplace = new RegExp(escapeRegExp(matches[0]), &amp;#39;g&amp;#39;); this.stringToReplace = this.stringToReplace.replace(toReplace, getSymbol(symbolName)); } } } var x = new SymbolReplacer(&amp;#39;dit $is een $test $test $test $is $complex gewoon woord&amp;#39;); console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing ES6 code</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2015/01/13/testing-es6-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2015/01/13/testing-es6-code/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my webpack workflow, and switched to 6to5, to be able to write more of my React code in ES6 than the current jsx transpiler supports (and because 6to5 just rocks!). You can find this workflow in my boilerplate-webpack-react project. Switching was easy. I&amp;rsquo;ve just replaced jsx-loader with 6to5-loader and everything worked correctly.
Writing code and developing is a breeze with this workflow, especially with react-hot-loader. I didn&amp;rsquo;t look into writing test though yet, and it took me a little while to find out how to do it, so I explain it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flux and cqrs</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/11/13/flux-and-cqrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/11/13/flux-and-cqrs/</guid>
      <description>About flux and cqrs, what do I want to write about this???
Things I want to find out. actions in the past: because it&amp;rsquo;s something that has happend. nothing todo about it.
deleting actions is not possible, only update. Store all actions in an event store for replay?
How about authentication and validation actions and flux. For example: action &amp;lsquo;MESSAGE_SUBMITTED&amp;rsquo;. But the message must be validated before it is added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the site, about me</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/10/04/about-the-site-about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/10/04/about-the-site-about-me/</guid>
      <description>My name is Thomas Coopman and I&amp;rsquo;m a 29 year old developer. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve officially started freelancing/consulting in my spare time. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason for creating this site and blog.
On this site you can find some more information about me. At the portfolio page you can see some things I&amp;rsquo;ve created. That page is empty at the moment but it will be coming soon.
I&amp;rsquo;m a developer, mostly a web-developer (backend and frontend).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating my first cordova app</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/09/29/creating-my-first-cordova-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/09/29/creating-my-first-cordova-app/</guid>
      <description>installation on ubuntu 14.04 prerequisites sudo apt-get install default-jdk
sudo apt-get install ant
npm install -g cordova android sdk http://developer.android.com/sdk/index.html
creating a project in folder cordova create test-app cd test-app
set the android emulator PATH=$PATH:~/Software/android-sdk-linux_x64/platform-tools/:~/Software/android-sdk-linux_x64/tools/  android installed Android 4.4.2 (API 19)
add a platform cordova platform add android
set everything in www run connect device in debugg
cordova run android
emulate android tools cordova emulate android
webview chrome://inspect/#devices https://developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating this site</title>
      <link>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/09/29/creating-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://infinitetree.eu/blog/2014/09/29/creating-this-site/</guid>
      <description>This is not valid anymore. The site is build with hugo
This blogpost will be a about the why, but mostly about how I&amp;rsquo;ve created this site.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created this site mostly for these reasons:
 Make myself visible on the web. Practice my design and web-development skills. Practice my writing (blog). Record things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned for myself. Maybe someone else will find something useful here.  Content The contents of this site contain information about me, to make me more visible on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>